<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The emperors answer to the French king's manifesto translated from the Latin.</title>
            <author>Leopold I, Holy Roman Emperor, 1640-1705.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1688</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 11 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A47719</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L1108</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R13327</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12935942</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12935942</idno>
            <idno type="VID">95756</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A47719)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 95756)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 388:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The emperors answer to the French king's manifesto translated from the Latin.</title>
                  <author>Leopold I, Holy Roman Emperor, 1640-1705.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 18 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Brabazon Aylmer ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1688.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Response to Louis XIV's decision regarding the Palatinate.</note>
                  <note>Dated (p. 18): Vienna, Octob. 18th, 1688.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Louis --  XIV, --  King of France, 1638-1715.</term>
               <term>France. --  Sovereign (1643-1715 : Louis XIV). --  Mémoire des raisons qui ont obligé le Roy à reprendre les armes.</term>
               <term>Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.</term>
               <term>Holy Roman Empire --  Foreign relations --  France.</term>
               <term>France --  Foreign relations --  Holy Roman Empire.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:95756:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:95756:1"/>
            <p>THE EMPERORS ANSWER TO THE French King's MANIFESTO.</p>
            <p>Tranſlated from the LATIN.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Brabazon Aylmer,</hi> at the Three <hi>Pidgeons</hi> in <hi>Cornhill,</hi> over againſt the <hi>Royal Exchange,</hi> MDCLXXXVIII.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:95756:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:95756:2"/>
            <head>THE EMPERORS ANSWER TO THE French King's MANIFESTO.</head>
            <p>IT is known to the whole Chriſtian World that when the Peace of <hi>Numigen,</hi> within a little after its Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluſion, was by the <hi>French</hi> King, many wayes vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lated, and large Countreys and Provinces, contrary to the Expreſs Tenour of the ſaid Peace, were, under the new and ſtrange Pretences of Re-unions and Dependen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies and the like, torn away from the <hi>Roman</hi> Empire, (there being a kind of a Mock Court of Juſtice Erected at <hi>Metz</hi> and <hi>Briſac;</hi> in which the <hi>French</hi> Miniſters acted the parts at once of Pleaders, Wit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ſſes, and Judges) that it
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:95756:3"/>was at laſt agreed in the Year 1684 upon the 15th of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> between His Moſt Sacred Majeſty the Emperor on the one part, and the Moſt Serene King of <hi>France</hi> on the other, that there ſhould be a Mutual Ceſſation from all Acts of Hoſtility, to be Inviolably obſerved for Twenty Years: And that, for the Honour of God, and the ſecuri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the Chriſtian Religion which was in Danger, and not without great Advantage to the <hi>French</hi> Affairs: It being permitted in the mean time to the <hi>French,</hi> that they ſhould have quiet and peaceable Poſſeſſion of almoſt a Sixth part of the Provinces which after the Peace of <hi>Numigen</hi> remained of right to the Empire.</p>
            <p>It is known alſo, with what ſtrictneſs in the mean time, and Confidence in the King's Word, and favourable In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terpretation of all ſuſpitious Actions, and Injuries, which His Majeſty the Emperour ſuffered, and which the Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces and States of the Empire often complain'd that they ſuffered from the Crown of <hi>France,</hi> the ſaid Peace on the Emperours ſide was obſerved; And how His Majeſty the Emperour truſting in the Faith of this League, was un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mov'd at every thing, inſomuch that His Subjects as well as Forreigners did wonder, that He ſeem'd not to be in any Fear, though His Frontiers lay open every where to the <hi>French,</hi> if they wou'd break their Faith, there being ſcarce above one or two Legions to defend ſuch a large open Country, the Confederates themſelves being call'd away to <hi>Hungary,</hi> and the Frontier Carriſons ſuch as <hi>Philipſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burg, Conſtance,</hi> and the reſt, being in a manner neglected and diſregarded: And all to the intent that His Imperial Majeſty might defend the Chriſtian Religion in Regions far remote, though He ſaw in the mean time the <hi>French</hi> Forces unreaſonably encreas'd, new and unneceſſary Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſons made on the bank of the <hi>Rhine,</hi> which belong'd not to the <hi>French</hi> King: and that Fraud and Violence was e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very where to be fear'd from Him.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:95756:3"/>
            <p>Certainly to this day there has not been any one Action on the Account of which the King might juſtly accuſe the Emperor of ſo much as attempting to break His Eaith, much leſs of actually doing it. Nay thoſe little ſuſpicions which <hi>France</hi> lov'd to make to it ſelf, as if <hi>Caeſar</hi> had in Thought, or in his ſecret Wiſhes inclin'd to any ſuch Thing, were by him immediately diſcuſs'd, and the Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter fully clear'd, by his great Moderation, in that he let alone what he might lawfully have taken, and generouſly omitted advantagious Opportunities, leſt he might ſeem by any the leaſt ſpark, to kindle the Flame of the <hi>French</hi> Jealouſie.</p>
            <p>Yet behold now again that Flame breaks out on a ſud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den which the <hi>French</hi> Court unwillingly cover'd over for a time. The <hi>French</hi> ſeize on the Dioceſs of <hi>Cologne,</hi> In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vade the <hi>Palatinate,</hi> Beſiege <hi>Philipsburg,</hi> and without ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerving any Law or Article of the Peace, or ſo much as the Ancient Manner of King's going to War one with a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother, the <hi>French</hi> King falls moſt unjuſtly upon the Emperour and the Empire, like one that had been long ſecretly a contriving it: And at laſt forſooth in His ſmooth-tongued faſhion, not when He denounced War, but when He had already begun it, He orders His Fallacious Memorial to be preſented us, in which He does not Excuſe but openly Avow the Violence and Injuſtice of His Arms, as if He had been provoked to a War, and did not bring it on a ſudden, upon thoſe who thought nothing of it.</p>
            <p>In thoſe His Letters (or that His Manifeſto) He publiſhes thoſe which the Compiler of 'em calls the Cauſes, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by the Moſt Chriſtian King is induced to take Arms again againſt <hi>Caeſur</hi> and the Empire, and by which He ſayes the Chriſtian World ought to be convinced of His ſincere de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire of the publick Tranquillity thereof; That forſooth His Sacred Majeſty the Emperor intends to make a Peace with the <hi>Turk,</hi> that He may turn His Arms againſt <hi>France.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:95756:4"/>
            <p>This He will have to appear, Firſt, In that preſently after the Peace concluded, the Emperour ſought new Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liances, which by divers Artifices and Craft were tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted at <hi>Ausburg,</hi> and <hi>Norimburg,</hi> contrary to the <hi>French</hi> Intereſt.</p>
            <p>Secondly, For that, Although the Emperor were per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaded even by the Popes Miniſters, to turn the Twenty Years Truce into a perpetual Peace, yielding only thus much to <hi>France,</hi> that what the <hi>French</hi> now enjoy'd for ſo long, by vertue of the Truce, they ſhould enjoy for ever, by this Peace, yet <hi>Caeſar</hi> would by no means yield to it.</p>
            <p>Thirdly, For that the Moſt Serene Elector <hi>Palatine</hi> has violently invaded and taken poſſeſſion of divers Goods, moveable and immoveable, which belong to the Dutcheſs of <hi>Orleans,</hi> by Inheritance, from the deceaſed Lords, her Father and Brother; and hitherto detains 'em, finding means to elude by divers Arts the Patience both of the King and His Brother, but depending all the while upon the protection of the Emperor, whom He therefore has perſwaded to make peace with the <hi>Turk,</hi> and to bring back His Arms to the <hi>Rhine,</hi> having enter'd into divers Leagues for that purpoſe.</p>
            <p>For that in the fourth and laſt place, The Cardinal of <hi>Furſtenburg</hi> contrary to the Holy Canons, the freedom of the Chapter, and the Inſtrument of peace, His former Faults which by the Emperor had been pardon'd, being brought into remembrance, and alledg'd againſt Him by the Emperors Embaſſador before a Seſſion of the Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, is openly and expreſly excluded from the Electoral Dignity, and the Moſt Serene Prince <hi>Joſeph Clement</hi> of <hi>Bavaria</hi> by baſe Arts, the Pope Himſelf being ſeduced, and a Brief of Eligibility, as they call it, obtain'd from Him, to the ſcandal of all People, and the Forces of the Proteſtants being brought into the Electorate of <hi>Cologne,</hi> is violently thruſt in, in His ſtead; with this malicious
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:95756:4"/>Intention, that he the ſaid <hi>Clement</hi> of <hi>Bavaria,</hi> being by entring into Orders, hindered from Marrying, if the Moſt Serene Elector of <hi>Bavaria</hi> ſhould happen to dye, as he is at preſent, without Iſſue (which may eaſily be, he expoſing himſelf continually to ſo many dangers in the War) then a Family ſuſpected alwayes by the Houſe of <hi>Auſtria</hi> ſhould be taken out of the way.</p>
            <p>By all which ('tis ſaid) it may appear clearer than the Sun at Noon-day, that the Emperour not regarding the deſolation of the Arch-Biſhoprick of <hi>Cologne,</hi> and the oppreſſion of the Catholick Religion, does endeavour to have War made upon <hi>France</hi> at the Charge and Hazard of the Electors, Princes and States of the Empire, that ſo the <hi>Roman</hi> Diadem may at laſt ſettle on the Head of the King of <hi>Hungary</hi> (now a Child) and all <hi>Germany,</hi> large as it is, being torn away from the Kings Friendſhip, may fall under the moſt miſerable Tyranny and Servi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tude of the Houſe of <hi>Auſtria?</hi> Even as theſe things are more largely and invidiouſly ſet forth in the foreſaid Writing.</p>
            <p>When His Sacred Majeſty, the Emperor, Read this infamous Libel, (infamous not to Him, but to the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor or Authors of it) and ſaw in it not ſo much as a ſhadow of Reaſon, but the moſt impudent Slanders wickedly forg'd, both againſt His Sacred Perſon and the Popes, as alſo againſt the Moſt Serene Elector <hi>Palatine,</hi> He eaſily perſwaded Himſelf, that it was quite contrary to the Sence of the Moſt Chriſtian King, and therefore far from having been Read or Approv'd by Him, but that rather it was Compil'd by ſome Malicious <hi>French</hi> Miniſter of State; for that He believ'd the <hi>French</hi> King would not ſuffer willingly, that His Imperial Majeſty, in a way ſo unuſual betwixt Crown'd Heads, ſhould be ſo unworthily Reproach'd, which matters he certainly knew in His Conſcience to be Falſe, or that the Reaſon of
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:95756:5"/>His own Actings, ſuch as they are, ſhould be written in ſuch an impudent ſtile, and with ſuch venomous reflecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and interpretations of things: And therefore His Imperial Majeſty doubted a great while whether He ſhould think it worthy of an Anſwer, and not rather paſs it over in ſilence: But foraſmuch as the <hi>French</hi> Court is not aſham'd, irreverently to Publiſh it, by its Miniſters as well in the Emperors own Court, as at <hi>Ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisbone</hi> in the Dyet, and endeavours by ſuch Falſe and Contumelious Reaſons to juſtifie Their bringing on Us a Cruel War, in a way little better than downright Treachery and Perfidiouſneſs, without ſo much as de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nouncing it before hand, as the Law of Nations does Require, and has been often Agreed; and without let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing us know what injury they had to complain of, but even deceiving us all by their freſh Aſſurances of con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Friendſhip, and pretended Kindneſs<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Therefore His Imperial Majeſty thought it neceſſary to demonſtrate to the World the vanity and inſignificancy of all thoſe undeſerved Imputations.</p>
            <p>To begin therefore with that which is the Foundation, on which all the <hi>French</hi> Reaſoning ſtands, <hi>viz.</hi> That the Emperor had reſolv'd to make a Peace with the <hi>Turk,</hi> that He might fall upon <hi>France,</hi> that can with no more Truth be charged upon Him now, than it was the laſt Year at <hi>Rome</hi> in a Propoſition made by Cardinal <hi>D' Eſtree.</hi> And as Impartial Judges will hardly believe, that ſo Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligious a Prince, ſupported by Gods help in the preſent War, and having all the ſucceſs He deſired, forc'd by no neceſſity, would ſo much as think of making a Peace with the <hi>Turks;</hi> without the Privity of His Allies, there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by to defile His Conſcience with the raſh Breach of a League made againſt the <hi>Ottoman</hi> Empire, and at the ſame time to incur the Juſt Cenſures and Complaints of the Pope, the King and Senate of <hi>Poland,</hi> and the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:95756:5"/>Commonwealth of <hi>Venice;</hi> ſo how vain a ſuggeſtion the other is, that His Imperial Majeſty ſhould have an intent to make War with <hi>France,</hi> (when He has neither an Army nor Proviſions at hand, nay when all His ſtrong Places, Cities and Provinces, as the event ſhews, by too much truſting the Kings Word, are left in a manner de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitute of Souldiers, and of all kind of Neceſſaries for Defence, and His whole Strength gone againſt the Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my of Chriſtianity) every one will eaſily ſee who will but take the pains even ſlightly to conſider, upon how weak and frivolous Arguments that ſurmiſe is grounded.</p>
            <p>Thoſe Arguments certainly amongſt thoſe that know nothing of the matter will ſcarce ſeem to bear the weight of a thin and brittle Conjecture; but to thoſe who do underſtand it they will appear to be mere Fictions, which yet if they were true, would prove nothing to this purpoſe. For who is there that can draw ſo much as a probable conſequence from hence, that becauſe the Emperor favours the innocent in defence of Himſelf, and of the Alliances which His Friends have made, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe He refuſes to turn a Twenty Years Truce into a perpetual Peace, without firſt hearing thoſe that are con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned in it, and without any diſcuſſion of the matter, becauſe by His Counſel and Help he ſuſtains His Father in Law, the Elector, that <hi>France</hi> may not have the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciding of his Cauſe: Becauſe Laſtly, He removes <hi>Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtenburg,</hi> the Man that has been ſo fatal to his Country, and promotes to the Biſhoprick of <hi>Cologne</hi> a Prince of great Expectation, of the Family of the Dukes of <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>varia,</hi> which has deſerv'd very well both of their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, and of that Archiepiſcopal See: Who I ſay can hence draw but a probable conſequence, that therefore the Emperor intends to take the firſt opportunity to make War with <hi>France.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:95756:6"/>
            <p>Nay <hi>France</hi> it ſelf, if it would but remember what was remonſtrated in Letters to the Pope, and to His Moſt Chriſtian Majeſty both by Words and Writing the laſt Year, by the Count <hi>Lobcowitz</hi> the Emperors Embaſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dor, would doubtleſs acknowledge, that all the other ſuperadded Arguments, and eſpecially that drawn from the League Eſtabliſhed at <hi>Ausburg,</hi> were vain and frivo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous. For this League brought on nothing that was New, but only Eſtabliſhed ſome Ancient Agreements betwixt the Emperor and ſome of the Circles of the Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pire: It Renew'd what was neceſſary betwixt the Princes and States of the Empire, for the Circumſtances of the preſent time: It tended to the hurt of none, but only to that which is moſt innocent, and allowed by all Law, their mutual Defence: And beſides it took in but a moderate number of Heads, and a ſmall Strength into it: And therefore the Mighty Crown of <hi>France</hi> did not need to be afraid of it.</p>
            <p>Truly the forgetfulneſs of the Compiler of this Libel is very wonderful, that he will not ſo much as remember that his own King, to prevent all juſt occaſion of quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>relling with the Emperor and Empire upon that account, before the Signing of the Truce, did Promiſe, that after it was Sign'd He would not be againſt the Empires Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſulting the beſt ways for its own Safety. Nay, and it was expreſly Declared in the very League of Truce, that ſuch Agreements of the Empire might be ſtrengthened by any kind of Guaranty of Forreign Princes. But the ſame Authors ignorance is yet much more to be admir'd, that he ſhou'd not know, that there is nothing more An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiently Receiv'd in the <hi>German</hi> Empire, nor nothing more Agreeable to its Laws, then that the Members ſhould alwayes moſt cloſely adhere to the Head for the Preſervation of the whole Body. And Laſtly, his Arro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gance or his Folly is greatly to be admired, that whilſt
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:95756:6"/>he preſumes it Lawful for his own King to make vaſt Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parations of War in His Kingdom, nay and under pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of a League unjuſtly made with ſome of the Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of <hi>Cologue,</hi> to ſend His Forces into that Arch-Biſhop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick, He ſuppoſes the Emperor in the mean while to have ſo little to do in the Empire, that He may not ſo much as meet with the Princes and States thereof to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſult about the Peace of their Country, without doing ſuch an injury to <hi>France</hi> as muſt be revenged by Force of Arms.</p>
            <p>His ſecond Argument has much the ſame degree of Force and Validity in it, <hi>viz.</hi> That the Emperor refuſed to turn the Truce into a Peace: If He had wholly re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſed it, and that upon other Conditions, that were not ſo unworthy of the Emperor, and noxious to the whole Empire, as thoſe which at that time happened to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed rather than propounded by the Court of <hi>France,</hi> had that been any Crime? The Twenty Years Truce ought certainly to have been ſtood to, and during the continuance of that a Peace ſhould have been Treated of, which His Moſt Auguſt Majeſty never refuſed, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided the King would agree to a Peace that was Honour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, maturely conſidered and Juſt: There ought there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore to have been a Meeting appointed, and both ſides heard, and all the Chief Controverſies concerning mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of right, in thoſe things which were attempted by <hi>France</hi> as well before as after the Truce, ſhould have been Examined; and then might have enſued a Peace, every one having their own reſtored to 'em, by common conſent, and ſuch as might have been likely happily to continue.</p>
            <p>The Moſt Chriſtian King might remember, that at His deſire the Truce was lengthened out to Twenty Years, both that there might be time enough to diſcuſs and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termine all Controverſies, as it was fir, and that the
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:95756:7"/>Electors, Princes and States of the Empire, might with the greater ſecurity take Arms againſt the Common Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my of the Chriſtian Name: And therefore that it cannot be without the <hi>French</hi> Kings breaking His Agreement, and violating His Word; that when ſcarce Two Years of the Twenty are gone about, and while the <hi>Turkiſh</hi> War yet laſts, He ſhould ſo change His Mind, that nothing now forſooth ſhould remain to be diſcuſſed or determined, but a ſixth part of the Provinces of the Empire, muſt at once by a full and irrevocable Right be made over to Him. Now this is what the Emperor could not Lawfully have done, if He would: It would have been contrary to Right, and to the Tenour of the Truce, and they who had thought themſelves injured would doubtleſs have withſtood it.</p>
            <p>Therefore His Imperial Majeſty excuſed Himſelf as to this matter; and leſt any the leaſt ſuſpition ſhould re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main, He not only declared ſeveral times by His Letters to the Pope, and by a Writing exhibited to the <hi>French</hi> King by the Count <hi>Lobcowitz</hi> then Reſident in the <hi>French</hi> Court, that He would keep inviolably the Twenty Years Truce, as well after the end of the <hi>Turkiſh</hi> War, as du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring its Continuance, but alſo if the King thought it ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary, He would confirm it by an Oath, to be depoſed in the hands of the Pope: In which when the <hi>French</hi> King did then acquieſce, and with all did obtain that His mighty Building of Fortifications, which He had begun and deſired to finiſh, though contrary to the Articles of the ſaid Truce (and of the Peace of <hi>Weſtphalia</hi> and <hi>Ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>megen</hi>) ſhould not be look'd on as a juſt Cauſe to break it, He promiſing over and over again the moſt ſincere and conſtant Friendſhip during the whole Twenty Years: Any one may hence eaſily gather how frivolouſly this ſame pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence is made for the <hi>French</hi> infraction of their League, and what laſting Peace can be expected, if ſuch idle
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:95756:7"/>Reaſons may ſerve, to break His Faith, and overthrow His Agreements, ſo that a Twenty Years Truce can hard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly laſt Four.</p>
            <p>As for the Third Argument taken from the Succeſſion in the <hi>Palatinate,</hi> His Imperial Majeſty do'es not ſo eſpouſe the Cauſe of the Moſt Serene Elector <hi>Palatine,</hi> as to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend it at all Adventure without its coming to a fair Try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al: But it is moſt evident that that Prince (who is famous all over the World for the Nobility of His Blood, the Probity of His Behaviour, and His great Wiſdom and Prudence) did not violently Invade the Countreys of the <hi>Palatinate,</hi> but enter'd peaceably, obſerving all Forms of Law. Whatſoever things did undoubtedly belong to the Dutcheſs of <hi>Orleans</hi> by Inheritance, he willingly let her have. As for what was doubtful not being willing to be blindly prodigal of what He had, He thought fit to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain it, till the Matter were clear'd by a Competent Judge.</p>
            <p>The <hi>French</hi> King has undertaken the Cauſe of the Dut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheſs of <hi>Orleans,</hi> and given notice to the Elector <hi>Palatine</hi> to yield up what ſhe pretends to: He appeals to the Court of Judgment, the Court <hi>Palatine</hi> of the Empire: This the King refuſes. What if the Emperor ſhould undertake the Cauſe of the Duke of <hi>Lorrain</hi>'s claim to his Inheri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance, for the ſake of his dear Nephew, and ſhould re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to let it be try'd in <hi>France?</hi> Has the <hi>French</hi> King more right in the Empire, than the Emperor has in <hi>France?</hi> Afterwards there being a propoſal of referring the matter to the Pope, the Elector <hi>Palatine</hi> admitted him as Media<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor <hi>(Arbitrator)</hi> whom he cou'd not allow of as a Judge without giving Offence to His own Court, by whom it ſhou'd be try'd, and without the conſent of his Kindred, He ſent a Miniſter to <hi>Rome</hi> fully inſtructed and informed. The Dutcheſs of <hi>Orleans</hi> ſent never a one. The Pope ſent a Monition to her, but all in vain; ſo that at laſt af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter a whole years ſtay the <hi>Palatine</hi>'s Embaſſadour was diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſed
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:95756:8"/>by the deluded Pope. And yet very lately the <hi>French</hi> King's Embaſſador here at <hi>Vienna</hi> the Count <hi>De Luſignan</hi> aſſures the Emperor that His Maſter was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd not to depart from the Arbitration of the Pope, though he was very averſe and unfriendly to Him. Thus the <hi>French</hi> King drills it on with vain Pretences, till me falls in with His Arms upon the <hi>Palatinate.</hi> And this is the true ſeries of the matter.</p>
            <p>That which is added concerning the Emperors being ſollicited by the Elector <hi>Palatine</hi> to make War upon <hi>France,</hi> and a League made to that purpoſe, is all a Fiction. Neither is the Moſt Serene Elector ſo imprudent as to ſeek any gain by War, when, fall how it will, it will be ſure to be moſt pernicious and fatal to His own Country.</p>
            <p>The laſt Argument remains concerning the buſineſs of <hi>Cologne</hi> for the putting out of <hi>Furſtenburgh,</hi> and thruſting in the <hi>Bavarian,</hi> which is ſo ſtuff'd with Calumnies, that from thence it may appear how deſtitute <hi>Frunce</hi> is of any Reaſon, or ſhadow of Reaſon to cover the Injuſtice of their breach of Faith.</p>
            <p>What the Emperor did at <hi>Cologne</hi> He did according to Right, and agreeable to the Laws of Juſtice, and His Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perial Office, and the Patronſhip of all Churches, there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto annexed. He did exhort the Chapter to chooſe him that was beſt and fitteſt for the Church, giving Reaſons why thoſe Qualifications were not to be found in the Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinal of <hi>Furſtenburg.</hi> He alledg'd his former Crimes upon no other account, but as they have been encreaſed by new ones. And the Emperor would willingly have forgotten all old Faults if <hi>Fruſtenburg</hi> would have laid aſide his old evil Temper, and were not found ſtill plotting worſe things than he was guilty of before. But He left every one of the Chapter their entire Liberty as well in as af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Election, He corrupted none of 'em by promiſes of Reward, much leſs did He Threaten, or uſe any Vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence;
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:95756:8"/>He did neither ſtir up any Foreign Forces to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Arch-Biſhoprick, nor did He ſend in His own, but remitting the whole Controverſie to the Holy Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtolick See, the only Competent Judge in this Matter, He quietly expected a Deciſion of it. Thus did the Empe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ror in the Empire: Did <hi>France</hi> do the ſame? But it may be the <hi>French</hi> King has more Authority not only in His own Kingdom, but in the <hi>German</hi> Empire. He violated not the Holy Canons, nor the Articles of Peace, nor the Liberty of Voting, whilſt without adviſing with, yea a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Will of the Pope, firſt by ſecret Arts, and af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terwards by a great Sum of Money He got the Cardinal of <hi>Furſtenburg</hi> into the Coadjutorſhip, by the help of ſuch Voices as He had bought, whilſt He made an unlawful Agreement or League at <hi>Luxemburg,</hi> Seventeen Months ago, and promiſed that He would not only ſend, but at His own Charge maintain a ſtrong Army in the Arch-Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhoprick whereby he that was thus pretendedly poſtulated to the Coadjutorſhip, being not confirm'd but rejected by the Vicar of Chriſt, ſhou'd be upheld even againſt the Will of God, whilſt laſtly He terribly threatned the Grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſt Princes of the Empire if they offered to come, or ſo much as to matter a Word againſt Him. It was His Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fences againſt the Apoſtolick See, and the Raſhneſs of His Actions, and not any hatred againſt <hi>France,</hi> nor any In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terceſſions of other Princes, nor any Conſpiracies that Men may dream of, that made the Emperor zealous againſt <hi>Furſtenburg,</hi> and enclin'd Him to prefer the Prince of <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>varia,</hi> one already Biſhop of <hi>Friſing</hi> and <hi>Ratisbone,</hi> a Young Man indeed, but of great Vertue and pregnant Hopes, and whoſe Family has highly deſerv'd of the Church. Is this a Scandalous thing? Let the People of <hi>Rome</hi> ſay, who at the Doors of the Conſiſtory in great numbers did moſt highly applaud it, when they underſtood that <hi>Jo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeph Clement</hi> that moſt innocent and good Prince, by the
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:95756:9"/>unanimous Vote of that Aſſembly, was to be Arch-Biſhop of <hi>Cologne.</hi> Let <hi>Italy</hi> ſpeak, let <hi>Germany,</hi> yea let <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> and <hi>Holland,</hi> where Men that hated the very Name of the Pope, at once both Learn'd and Taught others on this occaſion highly to commend Pope <hi>Innocent.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>His Imperial Majeſty does willingly acknowledge that He was glad when ſo great a Prince appeared as a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petitor in the <hi>Cologne</hi> Election, and that He moſt readily conſented to the Deſires of Him, and the moſt Serene Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor of <hi>Bavaria.</hi> But that this ſhou'd be done out of a wicked and baſe Deſign, that the whole <hi>Bavarian</hi> Fami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, ſuſpected by the Houſe of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> might the ſooner be Extinct, this, as it is a great Wickedneſs but to ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gine it, ſo the Boldneſs, Impudence, and Raſhneſs of this Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor, who durſt to write, and publickly object this againſt the Emperor deſerves to be puniſhed by the Hangman. The Imperial Court does not think of, much leſs practice ſuch Wickedneſs. What the <hi>French</hi> Court does they know beſt. No body will believe ſuch things can be done any where elſe. But all will eaſily believe, that which is indeed the truth, that this moſt Impudent <hi>French</hi> Writer had a mind to make the Houſe of <hi>Bavaria</hi> jealous and ſuſpicious of that of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> as it is the Cuſtom of theſe paultry <hi>French</hi> Politicians, to poiſon all Courts with the Seeds of Diſcord that being divided they may fall the eaſier.</p>
            <p>Thither to be ſure that tends, that according to the <hi>French</hi> Faſhion in a tedious digreſſion He endeavours to whiſper it into the Ears of the Electors, Princes, and States of the Empire, that the Empires deſign is to make War at their Coſt, and by the Ruine of the Arch-Biſhoprick of <hi>Cologne,</hi> and Oppreſſion of Religion to obtain the <hi>Roman</hi> Crown for His Son, that is yet but a Boy, and to bring all <hi>Germany,</hi> being withdrawn from its Alliance with <hi>France</hi> into a diſhonourable and miſerable Slavery.</p>
            <p>He endeavours to amuſe their minds with ſuch Stuff leſt
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:95756:9"/>they ſhou'd agree and join together for their true Honour and common Security, thinking that the <hi>French</hi> King will eaſily rout 'em all ſeverally, though if all ſhou'd joyn to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, they wou'd quickly drive Him away. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore He ſtrives all He can by Fraud and Craft, to cauſe <hi>Germany</hi> to forſake the Patronage and Auſpicious Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duct of the Houſe of <hi>Auſtria.</hi> But the Houſe of <hi>Bavaria</hi> is not ſo Weak, nor the <hi>German</hi> Nation ſo ſilly, as not to underſtand theſe Artifices which cannot eaſily be hid. And as the Moſt Serene Elector of <hi>Bavaria</hi> do's gratefully ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledge the kind Offices which the Emperor at his Requeſt did for his Houſe in the Election at <hi>Cologne,</hi> ſo according to its uſual Wiſdom, it will but laugh at ſuch little Sparks of Suſpition, as it has done already, having had experience of theſe prating Sowers of Diſſenſion; And will eaſily ſee, that there is nothing to be hop'd for from the <hi>French</hi> who ſeek but what they can get. But the <hi>German</hi> whoever he is, that is free from the Iron Yoke of the <hi>French,</hi> may eaſily ſee by the Oppreſſion of the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple even in <hi>Germany</hi> it ſelf where they come, and from the Condition even of their own Nobility and Gentry in <hi>France,</hi> whether comes nearer to <hi>Tyranny,</hi> the Governour of the Houſe of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> or the <hi>French</hi> manner of Ru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling; And will rejoyce truly that the <hi>Roman</hi> Crown do's not fall that way, whither the <hi>French</hi> Court has often ſhewn that they have deſigned it, and then eſpecially, when after their Ancient Faſhion without any regard to Honeſty, to their Faith, their good Name, or to Conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence, they have not only cheriſh'd the Rebels in <hi>Hungary,</hi> followers of the <hi>Turk,</hi> by ſending 'em Captains, Meſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers, Arms, Money and large Promiſes, but alſo, as it is done even at this day, have ſtirred up and encourag'd the very Enemies of the Chriſtian Name to War againſt His Imperial Majeſty. As it may be manifeſtly prov'd by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thentick
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:95756:10"/>Letters of the <hi>French</hi> Emiſſaries and of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bels and others, which are ready to be produced.</p>
            <p>And this is that which His. Imperial Majeſty has or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd to be anſwer'd with as much brevity as poſſible, to that Contumelious Libel or <hi>French</hi> Manifeſto, not to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jure the Reputation of the Moſt Chriſtian King, whom He believes to be induc'd to this unjuſt breach of the Peace, by the malitious and falſe Suggeſtions of thoſe, who ſeek Gain by theſe Troubles, and who He believes wou'd not approve of ſuch ill Language and unjuſt Railing againſt His Sacred Perſon, but to wipe off all the Scandal which this Impudent Writer has endeavoured to fix upon the Houſe of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> and which the Miniſters of <hi>France</hi> do every where ſcatter about, and to defend His own Inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence.</p>
            <p>And moreover that this His Cauſe may be more and more publickly known and teſtified to all the Chriſtian World He does publickly declare and call the Omniſcient God to Witneſs, that He never thought any thing of brea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king the Truce, but that He was alwayes firmly reſolv'd, and it is ſtill His true and ſerious purpoſe to keep it invio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lably, if it will at laſt pleaſe His Moſt Chriſtian Majeſty to ſtand to the Covenant of <hi>Truce,</hi> and the Declarations which He made and reiterated but the laſt year from <hi>Paris,</hi> and not to endeavour to make any alterations. But as for paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing this Truce into a firm and perpertual Peace, He per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſts in that, that He will moſt candidly and willingly ſhew forth all readineſs in endeavouring it, provided that a Commiſſion being appointed for the dividing of the Bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, and diſcuſſing the Controverted Rights, may pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed in that Manner and Order as is agreeable to the Laws made betwixt <hi>France</hi> and the <hi>Empire.</hi> Wherefore if there be any regard to Juſtice in the Moſt Serene K. of <hi>France</hi> (as it is hop'd) His Imperial Majeſty has good Reaſon to believe and truſt, that He will of Himſelf Chaſtiſe and
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:95756:10"/>Correct the Calumnies and Slanders of this Scandalous <hi>French</hi> Print, will withdraw His unjuſt Arms, reſtore Dammages, bring back all into its Primitive State, per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit the Moſt Serene Prince <hi>Clement,</hi> long ſince Legally Confirm'd by His Holineſs, to enjoy quietly the Electo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate and Arch-Biſhoprick of <hi>Cologne,</hi> and will remit the Cauſe of the Prince <hi>Palatine</hi> to a competent Court of Judicature, in which His Imperial Majeſty does promiſe that Juſtice ſhall be Faithfully and Impartially done: And Laſtly, That He will ſuffer the Peace which He ſayes He wiſhes for, to be procured in the time, manner and order as is ſet down in the Truce.</p>
            <p>But if He be not willing to do theſe things, none can then ſuppoſe there is any other cauſe for the <hi>French</hi> King thus to revive the War, then that the ſingular favour of the Divine Providence, and the wonderful defence it has afforded to the Houſe of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> are things diſpleaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to Him, or that He fears the great encreaſe and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>largement of that Auguſt Family, by their, late Victories which have carried the Empire beyond <hi>Belgrade;</hi> or that He has a deſire to raiſe up again the beaten and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed <hi>Turks</hi> by diverting our Arms, as 'tis ſaid He has promiſed them. Or Laſtly, That through too greedy a deſire, not only of aſſuring to Himſelf for perpetuity, what He has got for a time by the Articles of the Truce, but alſo of Conquering the whole <hi>Roman</hi> Empire, He thinks Himſelf not oblig'd by any Pacts or Covenants, but that He may break them at any time at His Pleaſure. Whatever it is, the Moſt Glorious King of <hi>France</hi> ſhall not eſcape the Infamous Mark of a Perfidious Prince that violates His Faith. And therefore His Moſt Sacred Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perial Majeſty does proteſt before God and the whole Chriſtian World, that the ſaid King is free to ſtretch forth His Hands either to the Fire or the Water, and either to
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:95756:11" rendition="simple:additions"/>abuſe the felicity of His preſent Power, or in time to fear thoſe Adverſities which he provokes the Omnipo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent God <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Anger to ſend upon Him. But as for Him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, being driven to the neceſſary Defence as well of His Provinces, as of the Sacred <hi>Roman</hi> Empire, the Electors, Princes and States thereof, He ſhall be blameleſs and free from all the guilt as well of the calamities like to follow from the War, and the effuſion of Chriſtian Blood, as of the <hi>Mahometan</hi> Superſtition continuing ſtill in <hi>Europe,</hi> and of the deſtruction of ſo many Chriſtian Souls miſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rably groaning under the Yoke of the <hi>Turk.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Author indeed of this Print boaſts and glories that His Moſt Chriſtian Majeſties Arms are p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oved juſt from Heaven by their ſucceſs whereſoever He moves 'em; but with what Truth let him ſhew if he can. His Impe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rial Majeſty being fully ſatisfied of the goodneſs of His Cauſe, is reſolved if it ſhall pleaſe God in this occaſion to give proſperous ſucceſs to the <hi>French</hi> Arms, He will never the leſs adore and Magnifie the ſecret Counſels of God, who has ſometimes Chaſtized and Corrected even thoſe whom He Loved, by ſuch as <hi>Attilas:</hi> But He is glad that He has cauſe to hope better in this World. The Moſt High has thrown down and humbled the <hi>Turk</hi> that broke his League but a little before it was ready to empire: And He will alſo throw down and humble the <hi>French</hi> Violater of a League, which ſhould have held Sixteen Years longer.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Vienna, <date>
                     <hi>Octob.</hi> 18th 1688.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:95756:11"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
